[Sung Si-kyung's We Would Meet]
So today, Mika Nakashima said she wanted to join us.
It's my first time meeting her too.
She said she can't drink alcohol and would like to have samgyetang.
I was going to make samgyetang, but I ended up making dak gomtang instead, with all the meat deboned.
We've got dak muchim and dak gomtang! It's a proper meal today.
And with that
I heard she's having a concert in South Korea in June.
I will have an interview
and ask her what she thinks about Korea.
[Mika Nakashima We Would Meet]
Excuse me.
Welcome.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Mika Nakashima.
Pardon me.
What's this?
It's ramen and
I heard you like alcohol, so
this is alcohol from my hometown.
Is your hometown Kagoshima?
Yes, that's right.
I did a little research.
Thank you.
It's whiskey. I don't drink whiskey myself, but
I brought it because it seems to be all the rage these days.
[Thank you for the gift]
[Today's guest: Mika Nakashima]
I made dak gomtang instead of samgyetang.
What's that?
Samgyetang has a whole chicken in it.
And it's served with glutinous rice.
Oh, it's like a hot pot.
It's a bit thick and has glutinous rice in it.
Dak gomtang is a lighter version than that.
Oh, it's mild.
People in South Korea make and eat it like this at home.
[Dak gomtang]
Is it really this authentic?
Try it and see for yourself.
- Thank you, I'll enjoy it.
- Please, dig in.
I got some delicious kimchi from a friend's store.
It might be a bit spicy.
Really?
Are you okay with spicy food?
I don't like it too spicy, but I do like kimchi.
Wow, it's delicious!
Oh, there's rice too?
I cooked it separately because if you put it together, the soup gets cloudy.
Rather than getting cloudy
it becomes thicker.
[This is really tasty...]
Is this made from chicken too?
Yes, it's from the same chicken.
I added more chicken to make the dak gomtang broth richer.
[Try a bite of dak muchim too!]
[It's delicious!]
[You've got great cooking skills]
I wonder if the kimchi is spicy. I'll give it a try.
It might be a bit spicy.
[Huh?]
[It's not spicy...]
[Gulp]
[The spiciness hits you later]
But it's delicious.
[Can you speak Korean?]
I know the common phrases.
I can understand what's being said, but I can't respond fluently.
Mika Nakashima is really famous in South Korea.
Thank you.
What's interesting is
maybe it's because of Park Hyo-shin.
That's right.
The cover of "Snow Flower" was such a huge hit
and also, people who like JPOP
have liked you for a long time.
[A leading figure in 2000s J-POP]
[Famous as the original singer of "Snow Flower"!]
[Actively working between South Korea and Japan!]
Even people who aren't fans know Mika Nakashima.
You have name recognition in South Korea.
Thank you.
I recently participated in the "Hamada Song Festival."
The "Hamada Song Festival"?
It's a show in Japan.
Mr. Hamada is the MC and everyone sings together.
There, you memorize lyrics for group songs
without knowing which part you'll sing
and when your turn comes, you have to sing it all from memory.
You have to memorize it?
That's the plan, but they give you about three minutes.
They played "Snow Flower" there.
I remember working really hard to memorize the lyrics.
[The lyrics of "Snow Flower" that I worked hard to memorize]
[Lyrics I still remember]
That must have been tough.
But it's truly a beautiful song.
Not to brag, but
I also watched the drama "I'm Sorry, I Love You."
(My song was covered) in that drama.
It was moving to have it used back then.
Have you ever met Park Hyo-shin?
I haven't met him yet.
I don't know if that day will ever come.
He's not the type to appear in public often...
Well, maybe someday if there's a chance.
Do you think he'll watch this broadcast?
[Hoping for a Mika X Hyo-shin meeting]
Hyo-shin, you should meet Nakashima-san.
Someday!
How many times have you been to South Korea?
Including work...
I've also come frequently for personal reasons.
I've lost count now.
[Also appeared on "Jae Friends"!]
Is this your first concert in South Korea?
[Scheduled for June 13 at Ilsan KINTEX Hall as part of the "Asian Tour 2026"!]
Have you ever performed at such a large venue in South Korea?
No, I haven't.
That's quite a challenge.
What if no one shows up?
Don't you always get anxious?
Yeah, of course.
Right? When the curtain goes up
I always end up having nightmares before a performance...
Like the curtain rises and there's no one there.
Or I go on stage without having memorized everything.
What? Really?
I only have those kinds of dreams.
I had a third try at the college entrance exam.
[The recurring nightmare I had during my third try at the college entrance exam was]
I hadn't studied at all yet
and I'm taking an exam that my life depends on.
Sitting at a desk
I have no idea! My life is over...
Even when I try to cheat, I'm being watched like a hawk by the proctor.
I wake up thinking, "What do I do? Aaaah!"
Is it really that bad though...
- Isn't it kind of cute, in a way?
- It's kind of like that.
Like a singer performing at a concert with no audience.
I often wake up scared from dreams like that.
I mentioned it earlier, didn't I?
Mika Nakashima is known not just among JPOP fans but also among South Koreans.
Everyone's like, "Oh, I know Mika Nakashima."
Thank you.
It would've been nice if you were at "Would Sing," too.
Do you know any of my songs?
I'm sorry, I'm not really familiar.
I'm sorry about that...
On the flip side, I'm happy.
Really? Why?
I feel a bit awkward saying this myself, but
I'm so well-known in South Korea.
Really?
When someone says, "Who are you?" it makes me kind of happy.
It's not like you're completely unknown.
I'm also working hard in Japan, but
I want to become a newcomer again.
It's really exciting to take on new challenges again.
It's more exciting than knowing everything already.
Meeting and talking to someone for the first time
there's a certain joy in that, isn't there?
So don't worry about me.
If you don't know something, just say so.
[Honesty is the best policy]
What do you usually like?
If it's food I like, just white rice.
- White rice is delicious, like rice balls.
- That's right.
I'm the type who's happy with just that.
But, you know, for health reasons
I do try to eat a balanced diet, though...
But I read in an article before that
white rice gets a bit of a bad rap.
- That's right.
- They say it makes you gain weight.
People say brown rice is better, but that's not always the case.
When I'm really hungry, I can eat about two bowls of rice.
I eat a lot, you see.
How much is two bowl of rice?
[*1go = about a large instant rice pack (300g)]
I said 2go... Oh, right, you don't use "go" here.
Maybe it's not that much.
I don't eat it all at once. I spread it out over the day.
Ah, right.
- I was really surprised.
- I don't eat it all at once, though.
I thought you were a competitive eater.
Still, I do eat about 2go a day by myself.
What about the side dishes?
Honestly, I don't need much in the way of side dishes.
As long as I have rice, I'm good.
[Now I'm trying to eat more side dishes too]
Why's that?
White rice does have some nutrients, but
still, it's not enough on its own.
I love it so much I could live on just that.
[Trying to eat a balanced diet for health reasons]
What's your impression of South Korea?
At first, I would come with friends sometimes...
I came more for travel than work.
For fun?
Everyone says South Korea's food is delicious.
I really just went around eating.
Well, I am South Korean, after all.
When you go to Japan, the food there is delicious too.
I wonder if it's the same feeling.
That's right.
In my opinion
I think it's because of the unique atmosphere and seasoning that you can't find in Japan.
South Korean cuisine.
And since there's no Japanese style in South Korea, too.
Is it because the cooking methods are different that it's so intriguing?
There's a show that introduces that with Yutaka Matsushige.
Like "K-foodie meets J-foodie" that airs on Netflix.
Oh?
That's been going on for a while.
[Is that person this person?]
Ain't I the worst? I am watching that show.
[(Trying to remember...)]
Should I call this Season 2?
With a model named Ayaka Miyoshi.
A new season has started.
I watched that and thought
that naengmyeon place looks good.
You should go there. It's delicious.
When I went last time
oh, when I came to South Korea
I searched for that naengmyeon restaurant
I went a few times, but it was closed, so I couldn't eat there.
Let's do it this way.
"I want to eat this, and I am around here."
If you ask, "Where do you think is good?"
I'll send you the information.
Is that okay?
[Then I'll leave it to you]
It's the most frustrating when Japanese people come to South Korea and
eat at places I can't accept.
If they go back saying, "South Korea is the best," it makes me so sad.
[(Totally get it)]
"There's a tastier place," or something like that.
- I see!
- Don't just go to tourist spots like Myeong-dong.
Myeong-dong is nice, but if you go a bit further
there's a deeper South Korea waiting for you.
I see.
It's a lack of information.
I just want people to eat the most delicious things possible.
Please, I really ask you.
Today, I'm eating right now, but...
If you were to go out at night, where's a good place?
What do you feel like eating?
What would be good?
Earlier for lunch, I had water parsley.
- Water parsley?
- Something like a water parsley hot pot.
What kinds of water parsley hot pot are there?
Isn't water parsley more of a supporting role, right?
Adding water parsley to something...
I had spicy fish roe stew.
Spicy fish roe stew.
[Had spicy fish roe stew for lunch]
Do you usually eat that?
That sounds more like a side dish or snack, especially in South Korea...
I had it with rice, though.
Which neighborhood is your accommodation in?
I forgot the name.
It's Goyang!
That's far away.
Yeah, it was quite a distance to get here.
I guess I need to look into it a bit more.
That's not really my usual stomping ground.
You seem to know this area well.
Goyang isn't Seoul, you know.
Right, that's what I said.
[Saitama: A prefecture located north of Tokyo, part of the metropolitan area]
It kind of feels like Saitama.
But hey, if you look around, you'll probably find it.
If it's Goyang...
A bit further, there's a place famous for Korean-style eel.
Korean-style eel?
You're curious, right?
Do you like eel?
Not really a fan.
Those tiny bones really bother me.
Eel bones?
[Eel bones?]
They clean it thoroughly, you know.
They do clean the bones, but
usually in Japan, you see.
Eel always has those tiny bones, you know.
I'll look into it a bit more.
Thank you.
Or if you could just decide on the menu, that'd be great.
Got it.
But I really like shrimp, crab, or clams.
I really love them.
So you like them, not that you can't eat them, right?
I love them!
[A city located at the southern end of Kyushu]
Are you from Kagoshima?
My father is around 70 or 80 years old.
We traveled around Kyushu for his birthday.
For your father's birthday?
Yes, the whole family, all ten of us.
We rented a bus with help from a friend in Japan.
We went on a hot springs tour.
[Oh, I see]
Actually, there are hot springs in Kagoshima.
Though they're not very well-known.
I lived in a very rural area of Kagoshima.
Nearby is a place called Yunomoto... In Chinese characters, it means "hot water."
And "place," emphasizing its hot springs.
There were hot springs nearby.
Ever since I was a kid...
For example, if my skin got rough
I'd think, "Going to the hot springs will fix it," and I'd go.
Like going to a hospital.
That's right.
At what age did you move to the city?
I was 18.
Back then, I was dreaming of becoming a singer.
I moved to the city after deciding to become a singer.
So, does that mean someone chose you?
That's right.
I guess you could call it a demo tape that I made.
Oh, it was that kind of era.
- Yes, that's right.
- I made a demo tape and went around to record companies.
Yes, and the interesting thing is
a friend knew someone who was a songwriter and composer.
I was close with them, so we often went to karaoke together.
They asked me to sing a guide vocal.
It seems they sent out that demo tape.
Probably hoping to get a song written for them.
Not to promote, but to sell the song.
I was doubtful, like, "Could I really become a singer?"
You mean as a guide vocalist?
Yes, I never expected it.
I'm not bragging, saying I never thought about it.
It felt like a miraculous stroke of luck.
Were you excited or nervous?
I was really nervous, honestly.
Do you usually get nervous on stage?
Yes, very much so.
Even during concerts?
Yes, it's really bad.
When it comes to broadcasting, I'm nervous to the point of death.
This broadcast right now?
No, I mean music broadcasts?
Oh my gosh
I understand about music broadcasts.
Like on terrestrial TV.
I understand.
When it's not your own sound, but a mix of many people.
During a live broadcast.
If you make a mistake, it's game over.
The whole nation is watching, and among them
I think there are quite a few people who don't like me.
It makes me want to scream, "Aaaah."
But when it comes to concerts
I don't get nervous at all.
The fact that they paid to come see me.
That's definitely true.
I'm only thinking about how to satisfy them.
Do you get nervous during concerts too?
Concerts too, and
just like you said, TV is more nerve-wracking.
I'm so scared I can't stand it.
I kind of get that feeling.
Your voice has such a unique color when you sing.
You're so charming, and your breathing technique is beautiful.
- Thank you.
- But I also
had the chance to sing a song by Mika Nakashima.
When I watch old broadcasts or materials
I think, "Oh, this person is nervous."
I guess it's because I'm a singer that I know.
That's how it is.
I've never been satisfied with a recording, or a live broadcast.
I understand.
I've never felt like, "Ah, I sang 100% perfectly."
That's true, really.
Always hitting about 80%!
"Is this good enough?"
That's about all I can do, really.
But that's just my personality, I guess.
Hmm, maybe so.
Aren't there quite a few people who don't really care about it?
There are!
They say "Enjoy it!" but what's there to enjoy?
[(Totally relatable)]
It's natural to feel nervous.
What's it like on Korean music broadcasts?
It's nerve-wracking.
I really get nervous.
Are the monitors okay?
Honestly, I'm not used to in-ear monitors.
Didn't you debut during the era when in-ear monitors became a thing?
I debuted in 2000, so
it is pretty close. I debuted in 2001.
[stage monitor]
I've been using stage monitors for so long
I'm still not quite used to these in-ear monitors that go in your ears.
I just can't seem to get the hang of them.
I end up not knowing what's what.
Exactly, they're just too close.
With stage monitors, you can feel it in your body.
Lately, I've realized I need to train with in-ear monitors.
Older Korean musicians aren't used to in-ear monitors.
They kept using wedge monitors, which is fascinating.
Plus, 20 or 30 years ago, the sound systems were a mess.
You couldn't hear a thing.
How did they sing without hearing their own voice?
Could that be considered a safety measure?
A safety measure?
Because there were no in-ear monitors.
They'd press one ear to hear their voice internally.
They had no choice but to hear it that way.
I wonder how they managed to sing in such poor conditions.
Those older musicians are just so talented.
Absolutely.
Just like we talked about, using their body to hear themselves.
They could sing anywhere.
They trained themselves to sing anywhere, without relying on technology.
That's true, but
wouldn't it be okay to just use one in-ear monitor?
A lot of people do use just one in-ear monitor, for sure.
That way, you can still hear the music.
Exactly.
But when I wear both, I start feeling uneasy.
[(Totally relatable)]
You can't tell if the sound is right or not.
Yeah, it makes it impossible to know for sure.
But without in-ear monitors
I can't do it.
Unless the monitors are really good
or if it's just a piano or guitar
in those cases, it's fine.
But doing all ballads like that is too much.
Many people do perform with just one in-ear monitor.
Everyone's concerned about hearing health, so they wear both.
They say it's best to get used to wearing both.
But
I end up taking them out anyway.
I see.
Do they cover Korean songs at Korean concerts?
No, they don't.
Is it too much?
But honestly, I want to do it.
What would be good?
[Hmm]
Give me a moment to think.
It's sudden, but could you tell me what it is?
Don't you have any favorite songs?
It's probably originally from South Korea, but I'm not sure.
From "My Sassy Girl."
"I Believe"?
That song, actually
was supposed to be my song to sing.
What?
It was taken away from me.
Really?
To Shin Seung-hun.
Please sing it.
I've covered it before in South Korea.
I really love that song.
There's a version of "I Believe" by Sung Si-kyung.
[Sung 20 years ago, "I Believe"]
There's a legendary producer in South Korea named Kim Hyung-suk
and I happened to be with his agency.
He had me sing various songs
but he felt sorry this time, so
he decided not to ask for a favor again.
[(Regretful)]
So Shin Seung-hun ended up doing it.
Yes, it was Shin Seung-hun.
But I do believe there's a connection between songs and their performers.
But it's a song that every Korean loves.
- Really?
- I'm really glad Shin Seung-hun did it.
I tried covering it, but it just didn't have the same feel.
A group from Japan
covered it.
Oh? Who?
["Full Of Harmony" did a Japanese version cover]
(If you're going to perform it at a concert,) I think it should be in Korean.
Since it's a Korean concert, after all.
I wonder if I can memorize it.
They'll be happy, for sure.
So, can you help me with it?
Yes, of course.
I guess I have no choice.
What will you do for me in return?
What should I do?
Please continue to love South Korea.
That's a given.
[What song would be suitable?]
What Korean song would suit Mika Nakashima?
Shall we exchange songs with each other?
Let's pick a song that suits.
My song?
Probably one of the most popular songs.
There's a song called "On the Street."
(The composer) Yoon Jong-shin actually had a specific intention when creating this song.
He made it thinking he wanted to give it to Mika Nakashima.
Oh? I think I've heard it before.
Send it to me later.
Originally, "On the Street" was written with Mika Nakashima in mind.
I ended up singing it.
Then, from my songs, as I please
can I send a few songs that I think would suit?
Sure.
Since it's a ballad, it matches the image.
I'm sure you can sing anything, but
the popular image is definitely ballads.
Will it have a similar feel, I wonder?
Yes.
The Korean male version of Nakashima.
Right, a slightly dark tone suits you too.
[What song would be good?]
What options are there?
But the pronunciation is difficult, as expected.
The performance is in June.
Already? Hold on a second.
Can I memorize the lyrics?
No, you don't have to sing it perfectly.
I tried my best, so please be a little lenient.
I'm sure Koreans will love it.
[Hoping the Korean fans will like it]
How many songs are we performing at the concert?
About 20 songs, I guess?
About 20 songs?
Do you dance too?
No, we don't dance.
We move around a bit, but there's no choreography.
Do you dance?
Yes, for the audience.
Really?
[If it's to make people laugh...]
Do you have any plans for activities in Japan?
There are plans, but
can't you talk about it yet?
Yeah, there's something...
Japan is really strict, right?
It's strict.
Honestly, we don't even know how much will be decided.
But there are various plans in the works.
The concert in South Korea was a huge success, so
I hope it makes them think, "Let's do it next year too."
I'd love to do it every year if possible.
It's the best, isn't it?
I'll come to watch.
Please sing a song.
- What?
- Then please sing a song.
Take your time to think about it.
Doesn't Japan have a guest culture?
Yes, it does.
Oh? It does, huh.
When doing a live concert in Japan
we invite friends
or they come to celebrate anniversaries and such.
I haven't done it much myself, though.
It's quite common.
In South Korea, it varies by person
but over 90% are divided into Part 1 and Part 2
and a guest comes as a surprise guest appearance in the middle.
They sing about two songs while the main artist changes outfits.
And if they come, I go next time.
It's done without payment, just among colleagues.
There's that kind of culture.
But in Japan...
It seems like there's nothing like that.
Artists perform solo
and it's over in 1 hour and 40 minutes!
But in South Korea, it's a bit longer.
I see.
I perform for about three and a half hours.
That's long!
[Three and a half hours?]
About 24 or 25 songs.
I'm having a concert in early May.
Early May?
The 2nd, 3rd, and 5th!
[It's outdoors, so come and join us]
Outdoors? That sounds fun.
If I think of anything, I'll suggest it.
Feel free to decline without any pressure.
Sure, I understand.
I've always dreamed of that.
Anywhere is fine, whether it's Korea, Japan, or China.
If there's a song you'd like to sing together
it can't be forced.
I look forward to working well together in the future.
Well, that's all from me.
That was Ms. Nakashima.
Would you like to say a few words to your Korean fans?
What should I say?
Thank you to all the fans who always support me.
I'll work hard for this live concert too.
I hope you'll come.
Please dance for us.
No, I don't want to.
Your Korean fans would love it.
But this time, it's a bit different from the usual live concert.
It's different.
I usually have ballet dancers.
I always bring them, but this time there won't be any dancers.
It's a mix of an acoustic feel and my usual style.
Is that format also used in Japan?
I do both, acoustic and the usual style.
No, is this concert specifically planned for South Korea.
Or is the completed stage going to be performed anywhere?
This tour follows that format.
So you're bringing that here, huh?
I'm looking forward to it.
Thank you for coming today.
- No, thank you.
- I had a great time, thank you.
That was Mika Nakashima.
[Bonus clip]
[Recommending songs to sing at the Korean concert...]
I think a song by Lee So-ra would be perfect.
What song by Lee So-ra should we recommend?
For example
the lyrics aren't too many, and the words...
[Si-kyung's pick is Lee So-ra's "Don't Leave My Side"]
Please send it to me.
No, I feel like I'm about to cry already.
It's decided!
Please, I'm asking for your help.
It's been decided with this.
Come to the performance to hear this song.
Hold on a second!
I'll do it if I can.
[Sung Si-kyung's "We Would Meet"]